<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Academic</title>
    <link>https://example.com/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://example.com/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project &#34;Energy Efficient School&#34;</title>
      <link>https://example.com/project/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/project/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;PROJECT DESCRIPTION&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years, the administration of our district and the republic has been taking a set of measures aimed at stimulating energy saving processes, namely the installation of new meters, raising tariffs for energy consumption at the regional level, the fight against non-payers, etc. However, this is not enough to solve the problem. Indifference and unwillingness to bear responsibility for anything in principle is a disease of modern society. The school continues to develop a responsible attitude of students to nature, observance of the moral and legal principles of nature management, and also activates civic consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In accordance with Article 24 of Federal Law No. 261, starting from January 1, 2010, the school is obliged to reduce, under comparable conditions, the volume of consumed water, diesel and other fuels, fuel oil, natural gas, thermal, electric energy, coal within five years by at least 15 % of the volume actually consumed by it in 2009 of each of the indicated resources with an annual decrease in such volume by at least 3%. Working on the problem of energy saving, we thought about reducing the amount of energy consumed, and also learn how to solve the problem of energy saving. I have monitored the school where I study on the basis of the &amp;ldquo;Declaration for 2015 of the institution &amp;ldquo;MBOU &amp;ldquo;Kurumkan Secondary School No. 1&amp;quot;&amp;rdquo; Information on the consumption of energy resources in the building, structure, structure / Educational building /&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2015, Kurumkan Secondary School No. 1 spent:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thermal energy - 1253 Gkl. for a total amount of 5647 million rubles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electricity - 56838 kW. for a total amount of 335344 rubles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The school has 338 pcs. incandescent lamps, which is 74% of the total mass of all lamps in the school. Also, the school has outdated kitchen equipment, which incurs additional energy costs, because cooking requires additional heating of the stove. There is no roof insulation, but there is an insulated basement. And our school is on a reduced class of energy and environmental efficiency of the building E= 37.121.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reasons for the current situation in the school were identified:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2015, energy saving programs were not implemented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to modern standards, the illumination of some rooms, utility rooms and other objects does not meet; the wiring is old, not all incandescent lamps have been replaced with fluorescent ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The duration of electricity consumption for lighting is 9 hours a day;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduction of information technologies into the learning process (the number of computers -2 has increased, which also increased the consumption of the electric field. To solve this problem, it is planned to replace incandescent lamps with energy-saving lighting sources.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SHIFT ITEMS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Requested funds:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Energy-saving lamps - 338 pcs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Replacement of lamps with motion sensors - 32 pcs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Replacing old kitchen stoves with induction stoves - 4 pcs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-save-energy&#34;&gt;HOW TO SAVE ENERGY:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Insulation of attics and basements (repair of thermal insulation of heating systems).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Insulation of facades, entrance doors and windows (or their replacement).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transfer of heating to standby mode during off-hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carry out timely scheduled checks of metering devices; in case of failure and malfunctions, do not allow the presentation of invoices for installed capacity;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monitor the operation of accounting and regulation systems,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monitor the proper operation of refrigeration equipment;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carry out timely replacement and repair of faulty taps, plumbing, process equipment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conduct briefings on controlling the consumption of electricity, cold water, computer and other equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To control the consumption of electricity, the correct operation of electrical appliances;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ensure compliance with the schedule of light regime in the premises and on the territory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Replace incandescent lamps with fluorescent lamps, which are 60-80% more energy efficient than incandescent lamps. Their service life is on the order of 6,000 to 20,000 hours versus 1,000 hours for an incandescent lamp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Replace incandescent lamps in the basement, utility part with motion sensors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Replace conventional electric hotplates with induction hobs. They cook food by creating an electromagnetic field that only heats the bottom of the cookware. As a result, there is no energy loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organize the participation of parents in the implementation of socially significant energy saving projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disseminate information about the results of the project on the school website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Campaign work should be carried out at the school (physics lessons, holding a decade in physics &amp;ldquo;Ecology and Physics&amp;rdquo;, information stands on energy saving at school, class hours on the topic of energy saving). Carrying out an advertising campaign to disseminate information:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Competition of posters, leaflets, wall newspapers. Posted throughout the school to give children the opportunity to critically reflect on the information provided and reflect on the process of choosing and deciding on energy savings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holding the event “What does it cost us to live a day?”. During the campaign, children think about ways to reduce the amount of electricity consumed at school and at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Energy audit of the house - calculates energy consumption in everyday life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Economic audit of energy saving. Calculate savings when replacing energy resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open lesson elective - protection of the project to save electricity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Replacing incandescent lamps&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Re-audit of the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project finish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;expected-project-results&#34;&gt;EXPECTED PROJECT RESULTS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strengthening the relationship between family and school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Realization of the rights of students to continuous education in the profile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research activities of schoolchildren.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obtaining visual and practical experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dissemination of information about the project. (School website, information stands in the school and district)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Note - in case of unstable prices for goods and raw materials, only the required funds are given without taking into account the cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;practical-significance-of-the-project&#34;&gt;PRACTICAL SIGNIFICANCE OF THE PROJECT&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solve a number of educational tasks;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Support for children&amp;rsquo;s initiatives;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obtaining practical experience of interaction between the child and the social environment;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save fuel and energy resources for the future generation;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reduce the risk of global warming;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save public money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Russia, despite prolonged difficulties, has remained an &amp;ldquo;energy superpower&amp;rdquo; - the owner of one of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest potential fuel and energy resources. Over 32% of explored gas reserves, 13% of oil and 25% of coal are concentrated on its territory. But even with such an abundance, the problem of resource conservation is one of the key ones for Russia. The problem of resource saving has its own specific Russian aspect - it is a wasteful expenditure of energy resources and energy carriers due to the extreme energy intensity of the means of production of the fuel and energy and industrial complexes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2008, the Russian-Indian cooperation in the field of solar energy was concluded. It is ideal for the two countries to work together on renewable energy projects. Russia also plans to use solar energy in remote regions where there is enough sunlight and the cost of electricity from diesel power plants is too high. India&amp;rsquo;s experience with its solar park in the state of Gujarat could be useful for Russia when it starts installing its solar power plants in remote parts of the country, such as the Altai Republic. Such an initiative as the Altai solar power plant received approval from Vladimir Putin. &amp;ldquo;For hard-to-reach places, inaccessible regions, remote regions, the use of alternative energy sources, renewable energy sources is an extremely important event,&amp;rdquo; the Russian president said last month.
A small German town in the south of Bavaria with a population of 2,600 is participating in an interesting experiment proving the viability of renewable energy in the future. Wildpoldsried currently produces 500 percent more energy than it needs for its own use from renewable energy sources and sells the excess electricity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The development and implementation of solar power projects in Russia has recently gone at an accelerated pace with a number of announced large, notable projects. Among such projects, there are several that will be implemented in the Crimea. Another project in the Far East is also contributing to the development of solar energy in Russia. In the Republic of Sakha (Yakutia), it is planned to build a 40 MW solar power plant in such a way as to fully provide the local population with electricity. Other projects in this area include solar power plants in Siberia with a total capacity of more than 254 MW, which Xevel is currently planning to develop. The objects will be located in the range from the shores of the Arctic Ocean to the territories bordering with Kazakhstan and barren lands on the border with China and Mongolia. “In 2015 alone, we are launching a 30 MW photovoltaic center in Altai, a 25 MW solar power plant in Buryatia, a 30 MW solar plant in the Omsk region and a 10 MW power plant in the Transbaikal region.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
